A Guide to the Virginia War History Commission, 1915-1931
Library of Virginia
- City Source Material, 1919-1927
  - Richmond
    - War Letters and Incidents
      - Dean, Herbert N. (omitted from Volume III) (Box 80, Folder 36)
      - Delbos, C. (Vol. III, p. 17) (Box 80, Folder 37)
      - Drake, James H. (Vol. III, p. 18) (Box 80, Folder 38)
      - Elwell, Alcott Farrar (omitted from Volume III) (Box 80, Folder 39)
      - Evans, Richard A. (Vol. III, p. 20) (Box 80, Folder 40)
      - Ezekiel, Gerald A., Dr. (Vol. III, p. 20) (Box 80, Folder 41)
      - French, Francis M. (Vol. III, p. 21) (Box 80, Folder 42)
      - French, L. Marden (Vol. III, p. 21) (Box 80, Folder 43)
      - Gilbert, J.B. (Vol. III, p. 22) (Box 80, Folder 44)
      - Goldman, J.C. (Vol. III, p. 22) (Box 80, Folder 45)
      - Hames, Jean (omitted from Volume III) (Box 80, Folder 46)
      - Hankins, C.O. (Vol. III, p. 25) (Box 80, Folder 47)
      - Hankins, C.O. (Vol. III, p. 25) (Box 80, Folder 48)
      - Hankins, C.O. (Vol. III, p. 25) (Box 80, Folder 49)
      - Hardy, Walter Scott (Vol. III, p. 25) (Box 81, Folder 1)
      - Harwood, Franklin A. (omitted from Volume III) (Box 81, Folder 2)
      - Hawkins, Horace T. (Vol. III, p. 26) (Box 81, Folder 3)
      - Hetzer, Floyd J. (Vol. III, p. 27) (Box 81, Folder 4)
      - Hinton, Edgar (Vol. III, p. 27 and omitted from Volume III) (Box 81, Folder 5)
      - Hinton, Hugh (Vol. III, pp. 27-28) (Box 81, Folder 6)
      - Hinton, Leonard (Vol. III, p. 28) (Box 81, Folder 7)
      - Hulcher, Junius J. (Vol. III, p. 29) (Box 81, Folder 8)
      - Jaffe, Louis I. (Vol. III, p. 29) (Box 81, Folder 9)
      - Johns, Turman (omitted from Volume III) (Box 81, Folder 10)
      - Johnson, J.P. (Vol. III, p. 30) (Box 81, Folder 11)
      - Jones, Samuel O. (Vol. III, p. 30) (Box 81, Folder 12)
      - Kennedy, Edward L. (Vol. III, p. 31) (Box 81, Folder 13)
      - Kennedy, Patrick A. (Vol. III, p. 31) (Box 81, Folder 14)
      - Kennedy, Thomas (Vol. III, p. 32) (Box 81, Folder 15)
      - Kenworthy, Frank (Vol. III, p. 32) (Box 81, Folder 16)
      - Kern, Mrs. G.T., letters to (Vol. III, p. 32) (Box 81, Folder 17)
      - Koster, Louis B. (Vol. III, p. 32) (Box 81, Folder 18)
      - Krough, Magnus B. (Vol. III, p. 33) (Box 81, Folder 19)
      - Latte, Joseph (Vol. III, p. 33) (Box 81, Folder 20)
      - Laws, Charles T. (omitted from Volume III) (Box 81, Folder 21)
      - Lee, Augustine Leftwich (omitted from Volume III) (Box 81, Folder 22)
      - Lichtenstein, Jr., Joe (omitted from Volume III) (Box 81, Folder 23)
      - MacNeil, Allan (Vol. III, p. 36) (Box 81, Folder 24)
      - Martin, Nancy T. (Vol. III, p. 36) (Box 81, Folder 25)
      - Mason, Randolph Fitzhugh (Vol. III, p. 37) (Box 81, Folder 26)
      - Matthews, Harry Anderson (Vol. III, p. 37) (Box 81, Folder 27)
      - Mazandian, Pat M. (omitted from Volume III) (Box 81, Folder 28)
      - McClellan, John Murray (Vol. III, p. 35) (Box 81, Folder 29)
      - McCrea, Leigh T. (omitted from Volume III) (Box 81, Folder 30)
      - McDaniel, John H. (Vol. III, p. 35) (Box 81, Folder 31)
      - McNeill, Allen (Vol. III, p. 36) (Box 81, Folder 32)
      - Meyer, Milton M. (Vol. III, p. 37) (Box 81, Folder 33)
      - Michel, Haney (omitted from Volume III) (Box 81, Folder 34)
      - Millar, Hudson C. (omitted from Volume III) (Box 81, Folder 35)
      - Miller, T. Ashley (Vol. III, p. 38) (Box 81, Folder 36)
      - Moseley, Vincent (Vol. III, p. 38) (Box 81, Folder 37)
      - Mustain, Marion Butler (Vol. III, p. 39) (Box 81, Folder 38)
      - Perry, George A. (omitted from Volume III) (Box 81, Folder 39)
      - Phillips, Harry N. (Vol. III, p. 43) (Box 82, Folder 1)
      - Priddy, W.L. (Vol. III, p. 44) (Box 82, Folder 2)
      - Quarles, John William (omitted from Volume III) (Box 82, Folder 3)
      - Richards, Harry Mason (Vol. III, p. 46) (Box 82, Folder 4)
      - Roosevelt, Archie (incident) (Vol. III, p. 90) (Box 82, Folder 5)
      - Rosenfield, Keeve (Vol. III, p. 48) (Box 82, Folder 6)
      - Rothschild, Albert M. (Vol. III, p. 48) (Box 82, Folder 7)
      - Sands, Charles B. (Vol. III, p. 51) (Box 82, Folder 8)
      - Scarborough, Jr., Jas. G. (Vol. III, p. 51) (Box 82, Folder 9)
      - Schoen, Ernest (Vol. III, p. 51) (Box 82, Folder 10)
      - Slatery, I.R. (omitted from Volume III) (Box 82, Folder 11)
      - Smith, Wilson W. (Vol. III, p. 54) (Box 82, Folder 12)
      - Stewart, Percy Lee (omitted from Volume III) (Box 82, Folder 13)
      - Strauss, Lewis (Vol. III, p. 55) (Box 82, Folder 14)
      - Sutton, W.C. (Vol. III, p. 56) (Box 82, Folder 15)
      - Szold, Albert (Vol. III, p. 57) (Box 82, Folder 16)
      - Thomas, Gersham J. (Vol. III, p. 57) (Box 82, Folder 17)
      - Thurston, John C. (omitted from Volume III) (Box 82, Folder 18)
      - Tredway, Betty M. (omitted from Volume III) (Box 82, Folder 19)
      - Tucker, L.A. (Vol. III, p. 58) (Box 82, Folder 20)
      - Van Landingham, Henry L. (Vol. III, pp. 59-60) (Box 82, Folder 21)
      - Vaughan, Everett Bryan (Vol. III, p. 60) (Box 82, Folder 22)
      - Wagner, Frank W. (omitted from Volume III) (Box 82, Folder 23)
      - Warner, Robert (Box 82, Folder 24)
      - Weatherford, C.P. (Vol. III, p. 62) (Box 82, Folder 25)
      - White, Fisk (Box 82, Folder 26)
      - Wiggins, Emmett L. (Box 82, Folder 27)
      - Winn, W. Garnett (Vol. III, p. 64) (Box 82, Folder 28)
      - Wise, Jennings C. (Vol. III, p. 64) (Box 82, Folder 29)
      - Word, Charlie (omitted from Volume III) (Box 82, Folder 30)
      - Word, Jr., William E. (Vol. III, p. 65) (Box 82, Folder 31)
      - Yale, Louise (Vol. III, p. 65) (Box 82, Folder 32)
      - Yarborough, Marion F. (omitted from Volume III) (Box 82, Folder 33)
      - Letters sent to Richmond News Leader (Box 82, Folder 34)
      - Unidentified Poem (Box 82, Folder 35)
      - Unidentified Letter (Box 82, Folder 36)
    - Post-War Conditions and Activities (Box 82, Folder 37)
    - Program - Armistice Day Celebration, 1921 (Box 82, Folder 38)
    - Miscellaneous - Program - Reunion of Confederate Veterans, 20-22 June 1922 (Box 82, Folder 39)
    - Report of the Richmond War History Commission from January 1921 to 1 April 1922 (Box 82, Folder 40)
    - Correspondence
      - Virginians of Distinguished Service, A-W (1921-1922) (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - Pre-War Conditions and Activities - Alexander Forward (1921) (Box 83, Folder 2)
      - Virginia Churches in War Time, A-J (1921-1922) (Box 83, Folder 3)
      - Virginia Churches in War Time, K-P (1921-1922) (Box 83, Folder 4)
      - Virginia Churches in War Time, R-W (1921-1922) (Box 83, Folder 5)
      - Virginia Churches in War Time, Miscellaneous (1921-1922) (Box 83, Folder 6)
      - Virginia Schools and Colleges, B-W (1921-1922) (Box 83, Folder 7)
      - Draft Law and Virginia Organizations - Requests for Service Records, A-L (1921-1922) (Box 83, Folder 8)
      - Draft Law and Virginia Organizations - Requests for Service Records, M-Y (1921-1922) (Box 83, Folder 9)
      - Draft Law and Virginia Organizations - Publicity/Request for Service Records, A-M (1921) (Box 84, Folder 1)
      - Draft Law and Virginia Organizations - Publicity/Request for Service Records, N-W (1921) (Box 84, Folder 2)
      - Draft Law and Virginia Organizations - Draft Laws, C-P (1921) (Box 84, Folder 3)
      - Economic and Social Conditions - Finance, C-W (1921) (Box 84, Folder 4)
      - Economic and Social Conditions - Agriculture, Food Production and Conservation, B-S (1921-1922) (Box 84, Folder 5)
      - Economic and Social Conditions - Industry, A-T (1921-1922) (Box 84, Folder 6)
      - Economic and Social Conditions - Transportation, A-W (1921-1922) (Box 84, Folder 7)
      - Economic and Social Conditions - Labor Conditions, C-W (1921-1922) (Box 84, Folder 8)
      - Economic and Social Conditions - Social Conditions, A-W (1921-1922) (Box 84, Folder 9)
      - Red Cross in Virginia, A-W (1921-1922) (Box 84, Folder 10)
      - Welfare Organizations, B-W (1918-1922) (Box 84, Folder 11)
      - War Letters, Diaries and Incidents, A-W (1921-1922) (Box 84, Folder 12)
      - Post-War Conditions and Activities, F-M (1921) (Box 84, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Correspondence, Invoices, Meeting Announcements, etc., 1921-1922 (Box 85, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence, Invoices, Meeting Announcements, etc., 1921-1922 (Box 85, Folder 2)
      - Warrant Book (volume) (Box 85)
    - Miscellaneous Lists
      - Lists Used by Richmond Branch in Campaign for Soldiers' Records (Box 86, Folder 1)
      - Lists Used by Richmond Branch in Campaign for Soldiers' Records (Box 86, Folder 2)
      - Lists Used by Richmond Branch in Campaign for Soldiers' Records (Box 86, Folder 3)
      - Lists Used by Richmond Branch in Campaign for Soldiers' Records (Box 86, Folder 4)
      - Lists Used by Richmond Branch in Campaign for Soldiers' Records (Box 86, Folder 5)
      - Lists Used by Richmond Branch in Campaign for Soldiers' Records (Box 86, Folder 6)
      - Lists Used by Richmond Branch in Campaign for Soldiers' Records (Box 86, Folder 7)
      - Lists Used by Richmond Branch in Campaign for Soldiers' Records (Box 87, Folder 1)
      - Partial List of Records Collected by Richmond Branch (Box 87, Folder 2)
      - Miscellaneous and Unidentified Material (Box 87, Folder 3)
      - Miscellaneous and Unidentified Material (Box 87, Folder 4)
  - Roanoke
    - Virginia Churches in War Time (Box 87, Folder 4)
    - War Work and Relief Organizations (Box 87, Folder 5)
    - War Letters and Incidents
      - Cocke, Jr., Lucian Howard (Vol. III, pp. 12-13) (Box 88, Folder 1)
      - Cocke, Jr., Lucian Howard (Vol. III, pp. 12-13) (Box 88, Folder 2)
      - Cocke, Jr., Lucian Howard (Vol. III, pp. 12-13) (Box 88, Folder 3)
  - Staunton
    - Virginia Communities in War Time - Augusta County and Staunton (Box 88, Folder 4)
    - Virginia Communities in War Time (Box 88, Folder 5)
    - Virginians of Distinguished Service (Box 88, Folder 6)
    - Virginia Churches in War Time (Box 88, Folder 7)
    - Virginia Schools and Colleges (Box 88, Folder 8)
    - Economic and Social Conditions (Box 88, Folder 9)
    - War Work and Relief Organizations (Box 88, Folder 10)
    - War Letters and Incidents
      - Chermside, Robert (Vol. III, pp. 11-12) (Box 88, Folder 11)
      - Gochenour, Roy S. (Vol. III, p. 22) (Box 88, Folder 12)
      - Knowles, Kinzley G. (Vol. III, p. 32) (Box 88, Folder 13)
      - Morton, Rosalie S. (Vol. III, p. 39) (Box 88, Folder 14)
      - Robertson, Archibald G. (Vol. III, p. 47) (Box 88, Folder 15)
      - Sackett, Dayton (Vol. III, p. 50) (Box 88, Folder 16)
      - Miscellaneous Incident (Box 88, Folder 17)
  - Suffolk
    - Virginia Communities in War Time - Suffolk and Nansemond County in the World War - A Community History by W.E. MacClenny (Box 88, Folder 18)
    - Virginia Churches in War Time (Box 88, Folder 19)
    - Economic and Social Conditions (Box 88, Folder 20)
    - War Work and Relief Organizations (Box 88, Folder 21)
  - Williamsburg
    - Virginia Communities in War Time - Williamsburg and James City County in War Time by Mabel Bradford Friend (Box 88, Folder 22)
    - Virginia Churches in War Time (Box 88, Folder 23)
    - War Work and Relief Organizations (Box 88, Folder 24)
  - Winchester
    - Virginia Communities in War Time - Winchester and Frederick County in War Time edited by C. Vernon Eddy (and earlier drafts) (Box 88, Folder 25)
    - Virginians of Distinguished Service - Nominations (Box 88, Folder 26)
    - Virginia Churches in War Time (Box 88, Folder 27)
    - Red Cross in Virginia (Box 88, Folder 28)
    - War Letters - Snapp, Louis E. (Vol. III, p. 54) (Box 88, Folder 29)
    - Post-War Conditions and Activities (Box 88, Folder 30)
- Series VIII: Selective Service and Volunteers, 1917-1921, 1925
  Following the draft into federal service and mobilization of the Virginia National Guard for Mexican Border Service and later war against Germany in 1917, a need arose to create a new militia force in Virginia. By order of Governor Henry C. Stuart, Adjutant General W.W. Sale issued a form letter authorizing the immediate formation of Home Defense organizations to be known as "Virginia State Volunteers" to serve during "the emergency." Two classes of Home Defense Organizations were created consisting of the Virginia State Volunteers and Virginia Home Guard. Lt. Col. Jo Lane Stern, State Inspector, was assigned the duty of organizing these volunteers. Companies of Virginia Volunteers were raised throughout the state including two battalions of infantry and over twenty individual companies. After the signing of the Armistice, most of these units disbanded or mustered out by 1920, although three companies passed over into the National Guard.
  The Selective Service and Volunteers series is housed in 16 boxes and 11 oversize folders and is arranged into four (4) subseries. Subseries have been designated for induction lists, Virginia State Volunteers, Virginia Home Guard and miscellaneous materials. This series provides an overview of Virginia Home Defense Organizations and information on the Selective Service procedures in the commonwealth.
  The Induction Lists subseries is housed in 5 boxes and 11 oversized folders and is arranged by locality (county and then city). The induction lists include the name of soldier or sailor, race, and date of induction. Some lists also include home address, army or navy service number, and date and cause of discharge from military. In addition there are a small number of correspondence between the Virginia Adjutant General's Office and local draft boards related to the enlistment and discharge of specific soldiers and sailors.
  The Virginia State Volunteers subseries is housed in 4 boxes. The Virginia State Volunteers was organized for home defense during the First World War between 1917 and 1918. Records are arranged by locality and include manuscript histories of units (published in source volume 4, Virginia War Agencies, Selective Service and Volunteers, 1926) and correspondence between the Adjutant General's Office and the Volunteer units. The correspondence, arranged by date (1917-1921), includes inquiries on organizing a volunteer unit, applications to form a company, and orders from the Adjutant General. There are records for the following units: Albemarle Rifles, Bath Rifles, Blue Ridge Rifles, Peaks of Otter Rifles, Berryville Guards, Colonial Rifles, Blue Ridge Guard, Hanover Grays, Henry Guards, Russell Guards, Tazewell Rifles, Washington Rifles, Clinch Valley Rifles, Hopewell Rifles, Lynchburg State Guards, A.P. Hill Rifles, Petersburg Guards, Radford Home Guards, Richmond Light Infantry Blues, Richmond Grays, Richmond Howitzers, Jo Lane Stern Battalion, Valley Riflemen and Winchester State Guards.
  The Virginia Home Guard subseries is housed in 3 boxes. The Virginia Home Guard were organized and controlled by local officials with the Adjutant General providing advice and guidance. The records of the Virginia Home Guard, arranged by locality, contain correspondence between individuals and the Adjutant General inquiring about forming Home Guard units. The majority of localities did not create Home Guard units. Notable records include a pamphlet containing the by-laws of the Alleghany Home Guard (City of Covington) and enlistment papers for the Danville Home Guard that list the name, address, date of enlistment, place of birth, age, occupation, color of eyes and hair, height, and marital status of each soldier.
  The Miscellaneous Materials subseries is housed in 4 boxes and 1 oversize folder and contains miscellaneous selective service and draft materials. These records include: bulletins issued to local draft board by the Virginia Adjutant General's Office from 1917-1919 describing selective service/draft procedures, copies of federal publications on selective service, blank selective service forms and miscellaneous ephemera.
  - Subseries A: Induction Lists
    - Selective Service - Law (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - Accomack County (Box 89, Folder 2)
    - Albemarle County (Box 89, Folder 3)
    - Alexandria County (Box 89, Folder 4)
    - Alleghany County and City of Clifton Forge (Box 89, Folder 5)
    - Amelia County - See Oversize Box 1, Folder 3
    - Amherst County (Box 89, Folder 6)
    - Appomattox County (Box 89, Folder 7)
    - Augusta County (Box 89, Folder 8)
    - Bath County (Box 89, Folder 9)
    - Bedford County - See Oversize Box 1, Folder 4
    - Bland County (Box 89, Folder 10)
    - Botetourt County (Box 89, Folder 11)
    - Brunswick County (Box 89, Folder 12)
    - Buchanan County (Box 89, Folder 13)
    - Campbell County - See Oversize Box 1, Folder 5
    - Caroline County (Box 89, Folder 14)
    - Carroll County (Box 89, Folder 15)
    - Charles City County (Box 89, Folder 16)
    - Charlotte County (Box 89, Folder 17)
    - Chesterfield County (Box 89, Folder 18)
    - Clarke County (Box 89, Folder 19)
    - Craig County (Box 89, Folder 20)
    - Culpeper County (Box 89, Folder 21)
    - Cumberland County (Box 89, Folder 22)
    - Dickenson County (Box 89, Folder 23)
    - Dinwiddie County (Box 89, Folder 24)
    - Elizabeth City County (Box 89, Folder 25)
    - Essex County (Box 89, Folder 26)
    - Fairfax County (Box 89, Folder 27)
    - Fauquier County (Box 89, Folder 28)
    - Floyd County (Box 89, Folder 29)
    - Fluvanna County (Box 89, Folder 30)
    - Franklin County (Box 89, Folder 31)
    - Frederick County (Box 89, Folder 32)
    - Giles County - See Oversize Box 1, Folder 6
    - Gloucester County (Box 90, Folder 1)
    - Goochland County - See Oversize Box 1, Folder 7
    - Grayson County (Box 90, Folder 2)
    - Greene County (Box 90, Folder 3)
    - Greensville County (Box 90, Folder 4)
    - Halifax County (Box 90, Folder 5)
    - Hanover County (Box 90, Folder 6)
    - Henry County (Box 90, Folder 7)
    - Highland County (Box 90, Folder 8)
    - Isle of Wight County (Box 90, Folder 9)
    - King and Queen County (Box 90, Folder 10)
    - King George County (Box 90, Folder 11)
    - King William County (Box 90, Folder 12)
    - Lancaster County (Box 90, Folder 13)
    - Lee County (Box 90, Folder 14)
    - Loudoun County (Box 90, Folder 15)
    - Lunenburg County (Box 90, Folder 16)
    - Madison County (Box 90, Folder 17)
    - Mathews County (Box 90, Folder 18)
    - Mecklenburg County - See Oversize Box 1, Folder 8
    - Middlesex County (Box 90, Folder 19)
    - Montgomery County (Box 90, Folder 20)
    - Nansemond County (Box 90, Folder 21)
    - Nelson County (Box 90, Folder 22)
    - New Kent County (Box 90, Folder 23)
    - Norfolk County - See Oversize Box 1, Folder 9
    - Northampton County (Box 90, Folder 24)
    - Northumberland County (Box 90, Folder 25)
    - Nottoway County (Box 90, Folder 26)
    - Orange County (Box 90, Folder 27)
    - Page County (Box 90, Folder 28)
    - Patrick County (Box 90, Folder 29)
    - Pittsylvania County (Box 90, Folder 30)
    - Powhatan County (Box 90, Folder 31)
    - Prince Edward County (Box 91, Folder 1)
    - Prince George County (Box 91, Folder 2)
    - Prince William County (Box 91, Folder 3)
    - Princess Anne County (Box 91, Folder 4)
    - Pulaski County (Box 91, Folder 5)
    - Rappahannock County (Box 91, Folder 6)
    - Richmond County (Box 91, Folder 7)
    - Roanoke County (Box 91, Folder 8)
    - Rockbridge County (Box 91, Folder 9)
    - Rockingham County - See Oversize Box 1, Folder 10
    - Russell County (Box 91, Folder 10)
    - Scott County (Box 91, Folder 11)
    - Shenandoah County (Box 91, Folder 12)
    - Smyth County (Box 91, Folder 13)
    - Southampton County (Box 91, Folder 14)
    - Spotsylvania County and City of Fredericksburg (Box 91, Folder 15)
    - Stafford County (Box 91, Folder 16)
    - Sussex County (Box 91, Folder 17)
    - Tazewell County (Box 91, Folder 18)
    - Warren County (Box 91, Folder 19)
    - Warwick County (Box 91, Folder 20)
    - Washington County (Box 91, Folder 21)
    - Westmoreland County (Box 91, Folder 22)
    - Wise County (Box 91, Folder 23)
    - Wythe County (Box 91, Folder 24)
    - York County - See Oversize Box 1, Folder 11
    - City of Clifton Forge - See Alleghany County
    - City of Fredericksburg - See Spotsylvania County
    - City of Lynchburg - See Oversize Box 1, Folder 12
    - City of Norfolk, Boards 1, 2 and 3 (Box 92, Folder 1)
    - City of Portsmouth (Box 92, Folder 2)
    - City of Richmond, Local Board 1 (Box 92, Folder 3)
    - City of Richmond, Local Boards 2, 3, 4 and 5 (Box 92, Folder 4)
    - City of Richmond - Notepads (Box 92, Folder 5)
    - City of Roanoke (Box 92, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous Induction Lists (Box 92, Folder 7)
    - Acceptance and Rejection Lists to Officers Training School (Box 92, Folder 8)
    - Registrations and Discharges (miscellaneous) (Box 92, Folder 9)
    - Registrations and Discharges (miscellaneous) (Box 92, Folder 10)
    - Registrations and Discharges (miscellaneous) (Box 93, Folder 1)
    - Registrations and Discharges (miscellaneous) (Box 93, Folder 2)
    - Registrations and Discharges (miscellaneous) (Box 93, Folder 3)
    - Registrations and Discharges (miscellaneous) (Box 93, Folder 4)
    - Registrations and Discharges (miscellaneous) (Box 93, Folder 5)
    - Registrations and Discharges (miscellaneous) (Box 93, Folder 6)
  - Subseries B: Virginia State Volunteers
    - Virginia State Volunteers and Home Guard - History (Box 94, Folder 1)
    - History of the Virginia State Volunteers, Muster Rolls and Correspondence (Box 94, Folder 2)
    - Albemarle County and City of Charlottesville - Albemarle Rifles (Box 94, Folder 3)
    - Bath County - Bath Rifles, Hot Springs, Virginia (Box 94, Folder 4)
    - Bedford County - Blue Ridge Rifles, Montvale (Box 94, Folder 5)
    - Bedford County - Peaks of Otter Rifles (Box 94, Folder 6)
    - Clarke County - Berryville Guards (Box 94, Folder 7)
    - Fairfax County - Colonial Rifles, Falls Church (Box 95, Folder 1)
    - Fairfax County - Colonial Rifles, Falls Church (Box 95, Folder 2)
    - Grayson County - Blue Ridge Guard, Galax (Box 95, Folder 3)
    - Hanover County - Hanover Grays, Ashland (Box 95, Folder 4)
    - Henry County - Henry Guards, Martinsville (includes Home Guard material) (Box 95, Folder 5)
    - Russell County - Russell Guards, Lebanon (Box 95, Folder 6)
    - Tazewell County - Tazewell Rifles (Box 95, Folder 7)
    - Washington County - Washington Rifles, Abingdon (Box 95, Folder 8)
    - Wise County - Clinch Valley Rifles, Norton (Box 96, Folder 1)
    - City of Bristol (failed) (Box 96, Folder 2)
    - City of Clifton Forge (failed) (Box 96, Folder 3)
    - City of Hopewell - Hopewell Rifles (Box 96, Folder 4)
    - City of Lynchburg - Lynchburg Home Guards (Box 96, Folder 5)
    - City of Lynchburg - Lynchburg State Guards (Box 96, Folder 6)
    - City of Petersburg - A.P. Hill Rifles and Petersburg Guards (Box 96, Folder 7)
    - City of Radford - Radford Home Guards (Box 96, Folder 8)
    - City of Richmond - Richmond Light Infantry Blues (Box 97, Folder 1)
    - City of Richmond - Richmond Grays and Richmond Howitzers (Box 97, Folder 2)
    - City of Roanoke - Jo Lane Stern Battalion (Box 97, Folder 3)
    - City of Roanoke - Jo Lane Stern Battalion, Company A, Alleghany Rifles (Box 97, Folder 4)
    - City of Roanoke - Jo Lane Stern Battalion, Company B, Roanoke Blues (Box 97, Folder 5)
    - City of Roanoke - Jo Lane Stern Battalion, Company C, Roanoke Guards (Box 97, Folder 6)
    - City of Roanoke - Jo Lane Stern Battalion, Company D, Lee's Minute Men (Box 97, Folder 7)
    - City of Staunton - Valley Riflemen (Box 97, Folder 8)
    - City of Winchester - Winchester State Guards (Box 97, Folder 9)
  - Subseries C: Virginia Home Guard
    - Accomack County (Box 98, Folder 1)